hey everybody welcome to this a2 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and become a member at
patreon.comlisteningtime
to receive my listening practice
seminars extra podcast episodes and my
sound training videos and remember that
if you become a listening time family
member you'll receive my advanced
podcast episodes okay so today we're
going to talk about learning in my
opinion this is a really important topic
because we should always try to learn
new things in life so first why don't we
talk about learning in school the first
place that you might think of when you
think of learning is school in the u.s
people usually start their first year of
school when they're between four and six
years old from that point on they have
many classes and study many subjects
until they finish high school and then
of course they can go to college if they
want so in total this is a lot of
learning but do students really learn a
lot during their education i think it
depends sometimes you learn a lot in
your class and sometimes you don't learn
much at all i'm sure a lot of you have
had this experience before you take a
class in high school and you're supposed
to learn that subject but you don't
remember much from that class when it's
over this could be because the teacher
wasn't that good or maybe you weren't
that interested in the class this
happened to me a lot
when i wasn't that interested in the
subject i just memorized the necessary
information to pass the tests afterwards
i forgot all that information however
when i had classes that i was interested
in i actually learned a lot for example
in seventh grade i had an english class
that i loved it was strange because most
of my other classmates hated this class
the teacher focused a lot on grammar and
we studied the structure of the english
language in detail i guess i'm not like
most people because this actually
fascinated me i still remember a lot of
the information that i learned in that
class even though it was 16 years ago i
think this shows that our brain can
learn a lot if it's engaged but it won't
learn if it's not engaged so how about
learning in your job
some people don't want to continue
learning after they graduate from school
they might think that once they get a
job they're done learning but we don't
only learn in school we have to learn
throughout our career this is important
because if we don't continue learning we
can't stay up to date this means that
our knowledge and experience can't help
us with current issues in our work
that's why we should always be looking
to increase our knowledge even if it's
not required so how can we continue
learning if we're not in school well one
way is to take courses to learn skills
and get certifications this can
definitely help you in your career but
to be honest you can learn without
taking courses you can use free
resources like youtube to learn all
kinds of things it's really simple you
just need to dedicate some time and
attention to this so what are some
things that could be useful to learn of
course you can learn languages you can
take courses to improve your soft skills
like communication and leadership or
maybe you can read about some new trends
in your field of work
you can choose to learn anything really
you can learn things that aren't even
related to your career if they're
interesting for you in the end the
important thing is to always be open to
learning new things okay that's all for
today remember to download the listening
time podcast and become a member at
patreon.com
listeningtime to receive my listening
practice seminars extra podcast episodes
and sound training videos and remember
that if you become a listening time
family member you'll also receive my
advanced podcast episodes also subscribe
to the channel click on the bell and
follow us on instagram i'll see you next
time
[Music]